{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Which sensor is used in magnetic levitation experiment?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Ultrasonic sensors",
        "b": "IR sensors",
        "c": "Hall effect sensors",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. What is the disadvantage of proportional controller?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Provides a constant steady state error  ",
        "b": "Improves stability of the system",
        "c": "Improves steady state error",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Which of the following controllers improves steady state error and also stability of the system?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "P controller ",
        "b": "PI controller ",
        "c": "PD controller",
        "d": "All of the above "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. A condition where integral control action drives the output of a controller into saturation, is called",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Self-bias",
        "b": " Repeat  ",
        "c": "Wind-up",
        "d": " Noise "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. Which of the following system provides excellent transient and steady state response ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Proportional action",
        "b": "Proportional + Differential action",
		"c": "Proportional + Integral action",
        "d": "Proportional + Integral + Differential action"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. The magnetic force, responsible for magnetic levitation is__",
      "answers": {
        "a": "  Magnetic attraction force ",
        "b": " Magnetic repulsion force",
        "c": "None of the above",
        "d": "Both of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. The MAGLEV is a_____ plant",
      "answers": {
        "a": "SISO ",
        "b": "SIMO",
        "c": "MIMO",
        "d": " None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. The ________ part of a PID controller is very sensitive to noise",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Derivative ",
        "b": "Integral",
        "c": "Both of the above",
        "d": "None of the above "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "9. If a copper disc is rotated rapidly below a freely suspended magnetic needle, the magnetic needle shall start rotating with a velocity",
      "answers": {
        "a": " Less than that of disc but in opposite direction ",
        "b": " Equal to that of disc and in the same direction",
		"c": "Equal to that of disc and in the opposite direction",
        "d": "Less than that of disc and in the same direction "
		
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. In a magnetic levitation system , the propulsion force is to, ",
      "answers": {
        "a": " Push moving part forward ",
        "b": " Lift up the moving part",
        "c": "Avoid derailing",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
